<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-07-08T03:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Go Up State</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/go-up-state.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/go-up-state.html</id>
    <published>2015-07-08T03:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-08T22:59:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="blog-header" style="background-image:url('/images/blog/trees.jpg');background-color: #A8C8C8;"&gt;

  &lt;div class="blog-header-content"&gt;

    &lt;h1&gt;Go Up State&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;h2 class="post-subtitle"&gt;a new website building service for awesome high quality results&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;!-- 🌿 🌄 🌿 🌄 🌿 🌄 🌿 🌄 🌿 🌄 🌿 --&gt;

    &lt;div class="author-block"&gt;
      &lt;img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/images/austin.jpg" alt="austin, founder of High Tops" class="profile-pic author-pic" /&gt;
      &lt;div class="author-name"&gt;
        Austin Samsel
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class="published"&gt;
     Published July 8, 2015
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="announcing-up-state"&gt;Announcing Up State&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up State is a service that gets your website launched — the State of Up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;" &lt;em&gt;Up State.&lt;/em&gt; "&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get it? Okay, cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So not only does Up State get your website launched, but it'll be a &lt;strong&gt;high quality&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;mobile-responsive&lt;/strong&gt; website, built in just one week. There's no quotes, no haggling, no weird stuff, just a flat-rate price of $999.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you get your website in the Up State then you can go upstate, meaning, you can get away and go chill in a log cabin or splash around in a waterfall because now you have all this free time you — or you could, you know, just put the extra time into working on your business, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that's Up State.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="is-this-for-me"&gt;Is this for me?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created Up State for two types of people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You're a &lt;strong&gt;small business owner&lt;/strong&gt; and you need a website to promote your business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're a leader&lt;/strong&gt; at a company that is launching a new product, organizing a conference, or starting a new marketing campaign and you need to promote your product by giving it its own website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you've probably already tried the following ways of getting a website up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do-It-Yourself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hire a freelancer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hire an agency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and you've had results ranging from &lt;strong&gt;wtf&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;meh&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;okay-we're-broke-now&lt;/strong&gt;. And maybe you've wondered if there was something else that just made the whole process easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="is-my-project-a-fit"&gt;Is my project a fit?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up State isn't for every project. It's meant for small, simple projects — usually, brochure-style websites that only require some basic functionality: contact form, content slider, a mailing list sign up form, and so on. These are the types of features that come prepackaged with most premium WordPress themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your project requires more advanced functionality, like eCommerce, webinar sign ups, subscription services, or a lot of design customization, then sometimes Up State is a great way to quickly jumpstart your project and put you ahead of schedule. Starting with a premium theme allows for the streamlining of a lot of design and layout decisions. It keeps costs down and saves time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up State makes sense for brand new projects as well as for existing, older websites that need to be totally refreshed. Up State websites are created with modern specs: a mobile-friendly responsive design, Google Analytics, global SEO, optimized page loading, and spam filters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="everyone-wins"&gt;Everyone wins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always negotiate for win-win outcomes. And I think Up State is a good example of that. As a developer/designer, I get to be more productive by offering a standardized, streamlined service. My clients get a great product that's tailored for them and they get to save time, money, and sanity. Awesome!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="up-next"&gt;Up next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm planning on creating a "playbook" that describes the whole process of building an Up State website. It will include cool stuff like which plugins I like to use and how I take my client's goals into consideration throughout. I'm also thinking about creating some add-on packages for more advanced analytics and visitor tracking – or possibly a more involved SEO package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there something else you'd want in an Up State website? I'd love to hear your ideas in the comments below. Or  you can contact me directly at &lt;a href="mailto:austin@hightopsnyc.com"&gt;austin@hightopsnyc.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
